https://www.aauw.org/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy – AAUW : Empowering Women Since 1881
Cookie Notice
This website uses cookies, including third party ones, to allow for analysis of how people use our website in order to improve your experience and our services. By continuing to use our website, you agree to the use of such cookies.
I Accept
Privacy Policy
home page
Site Navigation
Donate
Toggle Site Menu
Explore the Issues
Explore the Issues Sub-menu
Share via Email
Please read this entire policy. By continuing to use AAUW’s websites, you confirm that you understand and accept the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, please do not use AAUW websites. If you wish to purchase any AAUW products or services without use of an AAUW website, you may contact AAUW by phone at 800.326.2289.
Introduction
The American Association of University Women (AAUW), an organization advancing gender equity through research, education, and advocacy, is one of the nation’s leading voices promoting equity and education for women and girls and empowering them to reach their highest potential. What began in 1881 as a group of 17 like-minded women has grown into a powerful grassroots network with more than 170,000 members and supporters, 1,000 local branches, and more than 800 college and university partners across the United States.
Information regarding the American Association of University Women (AAUW) can be found on our website at www.aauw.org/about.
To assist us in achieving the above goals, we collect and process certain information you provide to us. We work hard to be good stewards of your information. This Privacy Policy is meant to help you understand what information we collect, why we collect it, and how you can control how we update, manage, export, and delete your information.
What AAUW collects and how
Anonymous and Aggregated Web Traffic Log Information
IP address, time, date, pages accessed, files downloaded, operating system, and browser version are collected and stored in log files. These log files are automatically purged after 60 days. AAUW’s websites also use cookies for session management, personalization and analyzing user behavior. AAUW’s electronic newsletters may contain web beacons in order to measure the effectiveness of our communications. This type of information is collected and shared on an anonymous, aggregated basis.
Personal Information (non-financial)
With a user’s consent, AAUW may collect all or some of the following types of personal information:
first and last name
physical street address including city, state, zip/postal code
phone number(s)
email address
professional and educational history including AAUW fellowships and grants
demographic information including your birth date, race, ethnicity, gender, sexual orientation, position, title, salary, affiliation
username and password
subject of inquiry
AAUW collects information that users provide when using online services including, but not limited to:
AAUW website registration
AAUW membership application
Event registration including online and in-person conferences, webinars, and community events
Subscriptions to AAUW products and programs including online learning products. Race and other demographic information may be required by a government agency that has provided grant funding for the opportunity to fulfill AAUW’s obligations. The option to provide or decline to provide race and demographic information is voluntary.
Subscriptions to and the download of digital communications including newsletters, public policy Action Alerts and petitions, public policy text messages, and research reports
Content contribution to AAUW when users “Share a Story” or comment on a blog
General questions, comments, and requests via “Contact AAUW”. We also may collect email addresses of those who communicate with us directly via email.
AAUW member search via the Member Services Database (MSD) directory. The MSD is a reference tool for AAUW members only. Users of the directory are prohibited from providing personal information contained in the directory to others or using it for promotional or survey purposes without the written permission of AAUW. Excessive use or abuse of the directory may result in loss of access for the user. AAUW will not include member’s contact information in the AAUW Member Services Database (MSD) if they opt out.
AAUW Work Smart Online and AAUW Salary Negotiation Facilitator Trainings registration
Financial Information
AAUW collects financial information to fulfill orders for products or services. When you join AAUW as a member, donate, register for an event, receive a financial stipend or pay your dues electronically, standard credit card information – card number, card type, expiration date, etc. – is collected through a third-party payment processor who is compliant with Payment Card Industry data security standards. The third-party payment processor provides AAUW and we retain the last four digits of your credit card number for purposes of issuing applicable refunds and identifying transactions.
Donors
We will not trade, share or sell a donor’s personal information to anyone else, nor send donor mailings on behalf of other organizations, unless we have the donor’s specific permission to do so.
What AAUW does with the information we collect
AAUW processes your information to provide the products and services you request from us.
AAUW exists for the benefit of its members and users and through the support of its constituents. Processing your information for the purposes described is necessary for us to conduct the business of AAUW. When AAUW uses your information we attempt to balance our legitimate business interests and the necessity of processing your information with how such processing impacts you.
If you have any questions or concerns about how AAUW processes of your information, please contact us by email at connect@aauw.org or call 800.326.2289.
We will ask for your consent before using your information for any purpose that extends beyond those described in this Privacy Policy.
AAUW may share information with third parties including those in the following categories:
affiliates of AAUW
conference registration and event service providers
payment processors
bulk digital communications and postal mail manager
online learning and communities manager
customer relationship management platforms
Work Smart Online promotional partners
AAUW may work with selected third parties to provide certain features on the Website such as social sharing functions. This privacy policy does not govern any information you choose to provide directly to such third parties. Such third parties have their own privacy policies that govern how they may collect, use, and disclose the information that you provide.
You may be asked by specific AAUW vendors to consent to their processing of your information when such processing will be subject to their privacy policy. We encourage you to review such policies closely and be sure that you agree to them before providing your consent.
Some AAUW websites may provide links — including any link through an online banner advertisement — to other sites on the Internet. These other sites are maintained by third parties over which AAUW exercises no control. The appearance of any such third-party links is not intended to endorse any particular company or product. If you decide to access any of the third-party sites linked to the AAUW websites, you do so entirely at your own risk and information you submit to them will be governed by their privacy policy, not that of AAUW. AAUW is not responsible for the services, content, conduct, or handling of materials by any third-party advertisers appearing on an AAUW website.
As part of our promotional efforts for Work Smart Online, AAUW may share information collected from Work Smart Online registrants with select promotional partners including local AAUW Branches and outside organizations. You may be contacted by AAUW with the option to opt-in to receive more information from our promotional partners. De-identified registration data and demographic information may be shared with promotional partners on an aggregated basis.
What are cookies and how does AAUW use them
As part of offering and providing customizable and personalized services, AAUW uses cookies and other online tracking technologies such as pixel tags and web beacons to store and sometimes track information about you. These technologies
provide you with personalized content based on your use of our websites;
enable you to more easily use our website by remembering and using contact information;
allow AAUW to evaluate, monitor, and analyze the use of our websites and its traffic patterns to help improve our websites and services; and
assist AAUW in learning what advertising results in traffic to our websites.
The types of technologies we use include:
Cookies
A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a Web server and stored on your computer’s hard drive. Cookies enable AAUW to identify your browser as a unique user. Cookies may involve the transmission of information from AAUW to you and from you to AAUW. Cookies may also be used by another party on AAUW’S behalf to transfer information to us in accordance with their privacy policy. Some cookies are “persistent cookies” used each time you access AAUW’s website. Other cookies are “session cookies.” Session cookies are used only during a specific browsing session. AAUW may use a session cookie, for example, to remember that you have already navigated through a particular menu. We may also use “analytics cookies” that allow web analytics services to recognize your browser or device and, for example, identify whether you have visited our website before, what you have previously viewed or clicked on, and how you found us. This information is provided anonymously for statistical analysis only. Analytics cookies are usually persistent cookies.
You may disable browser cookies in your browser or set your browser to warn you when a cookie is being sent.  You may lose some features or functionality when you disable cookies. Remember, also, that disabling cookies is browser specific. For example, if you use both Microsoft Edge and Chrome, you will need to disable cookies in each browser.
Pixel Tags
AAUW also employs a software technology known as a pixel tag or Web beacon. A pixel tag is a line of code placed on AAUW’s websites or in emails which allows us to analyze advertising and the general usage patterns of visitors to our websites. Pixel tags help AAUW manage our website by informing us what content or promotions are effective. Unless you consent, we do not collect personally identifiable information from you using pixel tags. You may not disable pixel tags.
Indirect Collection (Social Networking)
AAUW’s websites use third-party plugins that allow the sharing of web pages, social networking platform such as Facebook, Instagram, Twitter. We use the ShareThis plugin to allow you to easily share information from our website on various social networking platforms, email or text message. You control when you share information from our website using the ShareThis plugin. When you use social networking platforms and plugins, you share your information with them and their privacy policy applies to disclosure of that information. In addition, they may be able to collect information about you, including your activity, or may notify your connections on the social networking platform about your use of the website. Such services may allow your activity to be monitored across multiple websites for purposes of delivering more targeted advertising. Please note that their privacy policies apply, and we encourage you to read them. We may add new social networking plugins and buttons to our website from time to time.
Indirect Collection (Analytics)
Our websites use Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager, which are web analysis services offered by Google, Inc. to help AAUW analyze how users interact with our sites. You can learn more about these products from Google’s Terms of Service and Privacy Policy. AAUW also makes use of Google AdWords, another offering that uses cookies and remarketing technologies to deliver relevant information and advertisements to users who have previously visited AAUW websites. You may opt-out of the use of such web analytic products by downloading the “Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on.” We use Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager to analyze the use of our website. We do not transfer personal information to Google Analytics.
AAUW may retain the non-identifying information derived from our use of cookies, web beacons, Google Analytics, and other similar technologies for up to twenty-six (26) months.
Choices you have about your information
If you are a registered user of an AAUW website or an AAUW member, you may review, correct and change your personal information and your communication preferences by logging into the website and visiting your account profile page.
If you are a member and would like to correct, update, or deactivate your personal information in our database, please also contact us by emailing connect@aauw.org or calling 202.785.7700.
To unsubscribe from promotional email and other digital communications from AAUW, select the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any email from AAUW or contact us directly at connect@aauw.org. You may also send an email to request access to, correction of, or deletion of any personal information that you have provided to AAUW. Please note, we may not accommodate a request to change information if we believe the change would violate any law or legal requirement or cause the information to be incorrect.
AAUW vendors including those described in this Policy with whom you engage directly should provide information on reviewing, correcting, or changing your personal information or communication preferences within their systems.
Our websites do not support “Do Not Track” (DNT) codes which are used in the privacy preferences of web browsers.
How does AAUW protect your information?
The safety and security of your personal information is important to us. AAUW has appropriate security measures in place to prevent personal information we hold from being accidentally lost or used or accessed in an unauthorized way. We limit access to your personal information to those employees or vendors who have a genuine business purpose to access it. Those processing your information will do so only in an authorized manner and are subject to a duty of confidentiality.
We also have procedures in place to deal with any suspected data security breach. We will notify you and any applicable regulator of a suspected data security breach when we are legally required to do so.
AAUW’s policy on children’s information
If you are under 18 years of age, you may not purchase products or services from, and you should not provide information through AAUW’s websites without the involvement of a parent or guardian. We do not collect online contact information without prior parental consent or parental notification, including an opportunity for the parent to prevent the use of the information and participation in the activity. We do not knowingly solicit personal information from or market to children under the age of 18. If AAUW learns that we have inadvertently collected personal information from a person below 18 years of age, we will delete such information.
For Members/Customers in the EU
This Privacy Policy includes information applicable to residents of the European Economic Area (“EEA”) and users accessing the AAUW websites from within the EEA. If you are an EEA resident, this Privacy Policy provides you with information regarding your rights under the EU General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (“GDPR”).
AAUW is the data controller for the personal information collected from its members and customers. AAUW can be contacted any time at
American Association of University Women
1310 L Street, NW, Suite 1000
Washington, DC 20005
800.326.2289
connect@aauw.org
Transfer of Personal Data
AAUW and our websites are based in the United States and, regardless of where you access these websites, the information collected as part of that use will be transferred to and maintained on systems located in the United States. Additionally, in limited circumstances, it may be necessary for AAUW to require the transfer of personal information from a third-party entity within the EEA to the United States for AAUW to provide requested services to a customer in the EEA. In any such circumstance, AAUW will ensure that the transfer of information is made in accordance with Article 49 of the GDPR in that it will be done only to perform a contract with you or to implement pre-contractual measures taken at your request. Should it otherwise be required for AAUW to receive personal data from another entity within the EEA, to ensure there is an adequate level of protection for the rights of a European person based on the United States’ data protection laws, AAUW will make use of either the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield framework or contractual data protection clauses and similar legal mechanisms to safeguard the transfer, use, sharing and retention of personal data from the EEA in any such circumstance.
Your Rights
The GDPR provides you with certain privacy rights, including the right to access, correct or update your personal information. You may also request to have your information deleted, although we may retain information for backups, prevention of fraud and abuse, the satisfaction of legal obligations or other ongoing legitimate interests. You have the right to receive a copy of your information in a structured, machine-readable format. You may decline to share certain personal data, in which case we may not be able to provide you with some features and benefits. If you are an EEA resident, you have the right to object to our processing that is based on legitimate interests.
If you wish to exercise any of the rights granted to you by the GDPR, contact us via email at connect@aauw.org or via mail to the address set forth above, or you may submit the GDPR action form available on AAUW’s websites.
Right to Lodge a Complaint
If you are an EEA resident and you believe that AAUW has infringed your rights under the GDPR, please contact us by sending an email to connect@aauw.org or calling 202.785.7700. You also have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, including in your applicable Member State.
Sensitive Information
AAUW requests that persons to whom the GDPR applies do not volunteer any personal data considered sensitive by the GDPR, including racial or ethnic origin or sexual preference, even if a field exists for such information to be voluntarily provided. AAUW is required by certain governmental agencies in the United States to inquire about some sensitive information in relation to particular services it provides, but the disclosure of such information is always voluntary for the individual concerned.
For our Members/Customers in California
California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits our website visitors who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact us at:
American Association of University Women
1310 L Street, NW, Suite 1000
Washington, DC 20005
202.785.7700
connect@aauw.org
Please make sure to state in the request that you are a California resident.
How we make changes to this policy
When AAUW makes updates to its Privacy Policy, changes will be posted on this page. If you continue to use our website after those changes are in effect, you agree to the new policy. If the changes are significant, we may provide a more prominent notice or get your consent, as may be required by law.
Contact us
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or need to contact the AAUW to exercise your rights as a data subject under the GDPR, please contact the AAUW at connect@aauw.org or 202.785.7700.
Last Updated: August 13, 2019
Subscribe to our newsletter
Close Pop-up
You must enable JavaScript to sign up.
Email
Zip Code
Subscribe
Thank you for subscribing!
You must enable JavaScript to sign up.
Email
Zip Code
Sign Up
Thank you for subscribing!
